It was the greatest art heist in history
The Monuments Men is a war, drama, history film directed by George Clooney.
Based on the true story of the greatest treasure hunt in history, The Monuments Men is an action drama focusing on seven over-the-hill, out-of-shape museum directors, artists, architects,
curators, and art historians who went to the front lines of WWII to rescue the world’s artistic masterpieces from Nazi thieves and return them to their rightful owners.
With the art hidden behind enemy lines, how could these guys hope to succeed?
Lt. Frank Stokes, played by George Clooney.
Lt. James Granger, played by Matt Damon.
Sgt. Richard Campbell, played by Bill Murray.
Sgt. Walter Garfield, played by John Goodman.
Claire Simone, played by Cate Blanchett.
2nd Lt. Donald Jeffries, played by Hugh Bonneville.
The Monuments Men is a 2014 war film directed by George Clooney, and
written and produced by Clooney and Grant Heslov.
The film stars an ensemble cast including Clooney, Matt Damon, Bill Murray, John
Goodman, Jean Dujardin, Bob Balaban, Hugh Bonneville and Cate Blanchett.
The film is based on the 2007 non-fiction book The Monuments Men: Allied Heroes,
Nazi Thieves and the Greatest Treasure Hunt in History by Robert M.
Edsel and Bret Witter.
It follows an Allied group from the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives program that is given the task of finding and saving
pieces of art and other culturally important items before Nazis destroy or steal them during World War II.
The Monuments Men was co-produced by Columbia Pictures (in
association with 20th Century Fox) and Babelsberg Studio.
It received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $156.4
million worldwide against a $70 million budget.
The film explores themes of nazi, world war ii, based on
true story, art theft, post world war ii.
The tone is emotional.